<dataset><sequence><Authors>De Troch, M., F. Fiers &amp; M. Vincx</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Alpha and beta diversity of harpacticoid copepods in a tropical seagrass bed: the relation between diversity and species' range size distribution</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>215</Volume><Pagination>225-236</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gerdes, D.; Vanhove, S.; Vincx, M.; Lee, H.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Meiofauna response to iceberg disturbance on the Antarctic continental shelf at Kapp Norvegia (Weddell Sea)</Title><Series>Polar Biology</Series><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><Pagination>926-933</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Steyaert, M.; Herman, P.; Moens, T.; Widdows, J.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Tidal migration of nematodes on an estuarine tidal flat (the Molenplaat, Schelde Estuary, SW Netherlands)</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>224</Volume><Pagination>299-304</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R. &amp; G. Boxshall</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>An appreciation of the contribution of Arthur Humes to copepod systematics.</Title><Series>Journal of Crustacean Biology</Series><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>13-27</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Golani, D.; Fine, M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>On the occurrence of &lt;i&gt;Hippocampus fuscus&lt;/i&gt; in the eastern Mediterranean</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>764-766</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Corbera, J.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Amphi-Atlantic distribution of the Mancocumatinae (Cumacea: Bodotriidae), with description of a new genus dwelling in marine lava caves of Tenerife (Canary Islands)</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>134</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>453-461</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Moens, T.; Luyten, C.; Middelburg, J.; Herman, P.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Tracing organic matter sources of estuarine tidal flat nematodes with stable carbon isotopes</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>234</Volume><Pagination>127-137</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Goulletquer, P.; Bachelet, G.; Sauriau, P. G.; Noel, P.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Open Atlantic coast of Europe a century of introduced species into French waters.</Title><Book>Invasive aquatic species of Europe: distribution, impacts and management</Book><Publisher>Kluwer</Publisher><City>Dordrecht</City><Pagination>276-290</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>B&#246;ttger-Schnack, R. &amp; R. Huys</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Taxonomy of Oncaeidae (Copepoda, Poecilostomatoida) from the Red Sea. III. Morphology and phylogenetic position of Oncaea subtilis Giesbrecht, 1892.</Title><Series>in: Lopes, R.M., J.W. Reid &amp; C.E.F. Rocha (eds.). Hydrobiologia 156, Developments in Hydrobiology 156, Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Copepoda, held in Curitiba, Brazil, 25-31 July 1999.</Series><Volume>453/454</Volume><Pagination>467-481</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Vanaverbeke, J.; Gheskiere, T.; Steyaert, M.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Nematode assemblages from subtidal sandbanks in the Southern Bight of the North Sea: effect of small sedimentological differences</Title><Series>Journal of Sea Research</Series><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>197-207</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dewicke, A.; Rottiers, V.; Mees, J.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Evidence for an enriched hyperbenthic fauna in the Frisian front (North Sea)</Title><Series>Journal of Sea Research</Series><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>121-139</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Leschen, R. A. B.; Bullians, M. S.; Michaux, B.; Ahn, K.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Systematics of Baeostethus chiltoni, a subantarctic liparocephaline (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Aleocharinae): A Pangean relic or a more recent immigrant?</Title><Series>Journal of the Royal Society of New Zealand</Series><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>189-201</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Hyams, O.; Almogi-Labin, A.; Benjaminia, C.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Larger foraminifera of the southeastern Mediterranean shallow continental shelf off Israel</Title><Series>Israel Journal of Earth Sciences</Series><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3-4</Issue><Pagination>169-179</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Uysal, Z., A.E. Kideys, A.A. Shmeleva, J.A. Zagorodnyaya &amp; A.D. Gubanova</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Checklist of copepods (Calanoida and Podoplea) from the northern Levantine basin shelf waters.</Title><Series>Hydrobiologia</Series><Volume>482</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>15-21</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Hampel, H.; Cattrijsse, A.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Tidal, diel and semi-lunar changes in the faunal assemblage of an intertidal salt marsh creek</Title><Series>Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</Series><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>3-4</Issue><Pagination>795-805</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mu, F.H. &amp; R. Huys</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Canuellidae (Copepoda, Harpacticoida) from the Bohai Sea, China.</Title><Series>Journal of Natural History</Series><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>1-36</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Troch, M., F. Fiers &amp; M. Vincx</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Niche segregation and habitat specialisation of harpacticoid copepods in a tropical seagrass bed</Title><Series>Marine Biology</Series><Volume>142</Volume><Pagination>345-355</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Kato, Tetsuya; Pleijel, Fredrik</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>A revision of &lt;i&gt;Paranaitis&lt;/i&gt; Southern, 1914 (Polychaeta: Phyllodocidae)</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>138</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>379-429</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Faasse, M.; Van Moorsel, G.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>The North-American amphipods, Melita nitida Smith, 1873 and Incisocalliope aestuarius (Watling and Maurer, 1973) (Crustacea: Amphipoda: Gammaridea), introduced to the Western Scheldt estuary (The Netherlands)</Title><Series>Aquatic Ecology</Series><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>13-22</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Klautau, M.; Valentine, C.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Clathrina&lt;/i&gt; (Porifera, Calcarea).</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>139</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>1-62</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Giangrande, A.; Delos, A. L.; Fraschetti, S.; Musco, L.; Licciano, M.; Terlizzi, A.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Polychaete assemblages along a rocky shore on the South Adriatic coast (Mediterranean Sea): patterns of spatial distribution</Title><Series>Marine Biology</Series><Volume>143</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1109-1116</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mastrototaro, F.; Matarrese, A.; D'Onghia, G.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Occurrence of &lt;i&gt;Musculista senhousia&lt;/i&gt; (Mollusca: Bivalvia) in the Taranto seas (eastern-central Mediterranean Sea)</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the UK</Series><Volume>83</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1279-1280</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Hampel, H.; Cattrijsse, A.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Habitat value of a developing estuarine brackish marsh for fish and macrocrustaceans</Title><Series>ICES Journal of Marine Science</Series><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>278-289</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Steyaert, M.; Vanaverbeke, J.; Vanreusel, A.; Barranguet, C.; Lucas, C.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>The importance of fine-scale, vertical profiles in characterising nematode community structure</Title><Series>Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</Series><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>353-366</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Book review: Martin, Joel W., and George E. Davis. 2001. An Updated Classification of the Recent Crustacea. Natural History Museum of Los Angeles County Contributions in Science 39: 1-124.</Title><Series>Journal of Crustacean Biology</Series><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>495-497</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mostafawi, N.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Recent ostracods from the Persian gulf</Title><Series>Senckenbergiana maritima</Series><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>1-2</Issue><Pagination>51-75</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Karaytug, S. &amp; R. Huys</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Taxonomic position of and generic distinction between Parepactophanes Kunz, 1935 and Taurocletodes Kunz, 1975 (Copepoda, Canthocamptidae incertae sedis), with description of a new species from the Black Sea</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>140</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>469-486</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Remerie, T.; Calderon, J.; Deprez, T.; Mees, J.; Vanfleteren, J.; Vanreusel, A.; Vierstraete, A.; Vincx, M.; Wittmann, K.; Wooldridge, T.; Bulckaen, B.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Phylogenetic relationships within the Mysidae (Crustacea, Peracarida, Mysida) based on nuclear 18S ribosomal RNA sequences</Title><Series>Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution</Series><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>770-777</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Ahn, K.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Moorea zealandica, new genus and species from New Zealand with a discussion of its phylogenetic relationships (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Aleocharinae)</Title><Series>New Zealand Journal of Zoology</Series><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>255-261</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Muthumbi, A. W.; Vanreusel, A.; Duineveld, G.; Soetaert, K.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Nematode Community Structure along the Continental Slope off the Kenyan Coast, Western Indian Ocean</Title><Series>International Review of Hydrobiology</Series><Volume>89</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>188-205</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheskiere, T.; Hoste, E.; Vanaverbeke, J.; Vincx, M.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Horizontal zonation patterns and feeding structure of marine nematode assemblages on a macrotidal, ultra-dissipative sandy beach (De Panne, Belgium)</Title><Series>Journal of Sea Research</Series><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>211-226</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Porter, J.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Morphological and genetic characteristics of erect subtidal species of Alcyonidium (Ctenostomata: Bryozoa)</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the UK</Series><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>243-252</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Ahn, K.; Ashe, J. S.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Phylogeny of the Myllaenini and related taxa (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Aleocharinae)</Title><Series>Cladistics</Series><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>123-138</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Golani, D.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>First record of the muzzled blenny (Osteichthyes: Blenniidae: Omobranchus punctatus) from the Mediterranean, with remarks on ship-mediated fish introduction</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the UK</Series><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>851-852</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R. &amp; S.J. Song</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>The Ismardiidae Leigh-Sharpe (Copepoda, Harpacticoida Incertae Sedis): Enigmatic as Ever?</Title><Series>Journal of Crustacean Biology</Series><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>37-53</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Fockedey, N.; Mees, J.; Vangheluwe, M.; Verslycke, T.; Janssen, C. R.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Temperature and salinity effects on post-marsupial growth of Neomysis integer (Crustacea: Mysidacea)</Title><Series>Journal of Experimental Marine Biology and Ecology</Series><Volume>326</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>27-47</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R., S. Ohtsuka, S. Conroy-Dalton &amp; Y. Kikuchi</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Description of two new species of Neotachidius Shen &amp; Tai, 1963 (Copepoda, Harpacticoida, Tachidiidae) from Korean brackish waters and proposal of a new genus for Tachidius (Tachidius) vicinospinalis Shen &amp; Tai, 1964</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>143</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>133-159</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Fockedey, N.; Ghekiere, A.; Bruwiere, S.; Janssen, C. R.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Effect of salinity and temperature on the intra-marsupial development of the brackish water mysid Neomysis integer (Crustacea: Mysidacea)</Title><Series>Marine Biology</Series><Volume>148</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1339-1356</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Steyaert, M.; Moodley, L.; Vanaverbeke, J.; Vandewiele, S.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Laboratory experiments on the infaunal activity of intertidal nematodes</Title><Series>Hydrobiologia</Series><Volume>540</Volume><Issue>1-3</Issue><Pagination>217-223</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Musco, Luigi; Giangrande, Adriana</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Mediterranean Syllidae (Annelida: Polychaeta) revisited: biogeography, diversity and species fidelity to environmental features</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>304</Volume><Pagination>143-153 + 4 pp. Supplementary appendix</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Moens, T.; Dos Santos, G.; Thompson, F.; Swings, J.; Fons&#234;ca-Genevois, V.; Vincx, M.; De Mesel, I.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Do nematode mucus secretions affect bacterial growth?</Title><Series>Aquatic Microbial Ecology</Series><Volume>40</Volume><Pagination>77-83</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bick, A.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Redescription of &lt;i&gt;Fabriciola tonerella&lt;/i&gt; Banse, 1959, and a new record of &lt;i&gt;Novafabricia infratorquata&lt;/i&gt; (Fitzhugh, 1983) from the Mediterranean Sea, with a key for the Fabriciinae (Annelida: Polychaeta) of the Mediterranean Sea and the north-east Atlantic</Title><Series>Zoologischer Anzeiger - A Journal of Comparative Zoology</Series><Volume>244</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>137-152</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Troch, M.; Vandepitte, L.; Raes, M.; Su&#224;rez-Morales, E.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>A field colonization experiment with meiofauna and seagrass mimics: effect of time, distance and leaf surface area</Title><Series>Marine Biology</Series><Volume>148</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>73-86</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheskiere, T.; Vincx, M.; Weslawski, J. M.; Scapini, F.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Meiofauna as descriptor of tourism-induced changes at sandy beaches</Title><Series>Marine Environmental Research</Series><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>245-265</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheskiere, T.; Vincx, M.; Urban-Malinga, B.; Rossano, C.; Scapini, F.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Nematodes from wave-dominated sandy beaches: diversity, zonation patterns and testing of the isocommunities concept</Title><Series>Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</Series><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>1-2</Issue><Pagination>365-375</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Buschbaum, C.; Gutow, L.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Mass occurrence of an introduced crustacean (Caprella cf. mutica) in the south-eastern North Sea</Title><Series>Helgoland Marine Research</Series><Volume>59</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>252-253</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Rueness, J.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Life history and molecular sequences of &lt;i&gt;Gracilaria vermiculophylla&lt;/i&gt; (Gracilariales, Rhodophyta), a new introduction to European waters</Title><Series>Phycologia</Series><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>120-128</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Ivanenko, V.N., D. Defaye &amp; R. Huys</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>A new species of Ambilimbus nom. nov., a replacement name for Amphicrossus Huys, 1991 (Copepoda, Cyclopoida, Erebonasteridae), from the Mid-Atlantic Ridge at 36&#176;N (hydrothermal vent site Rainbow)</Title><Series>Marine Biology Research</Series><Volume>1</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>233-241</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Zagami, G., G. Costanzo &amp; N. Crescenti</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>First record in Mediterranean Sea and redescription of the bentho-planktonic calanoid copepod species Pseudocyclops xiphophorus Wells, 1967.</Title><Series>Journal of Marine Systems</Series><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>1-2</Issue><Pagination>67-76</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Herk&#252;l, K.; Kotta, J.; Kotta, I.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Distribution and population characteristics of the alien talitrid amphipod Orchestia cavimana in relation to environmental conditions in the Northeastern Baltic Sea</Title><Series>Helgoland Marine Research</Series><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>121-126</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bastrop, R.; Blank, M.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Multiple Invasions &#8211; A Polychaete Genus Enters the Baltic Sea</Title><Series>Biological Invasions</Series><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><Pagination>1195-1200</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R. &amp; S. Conroy-Dalton</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Revision of the genus Evansula T. Scott, 1906 (Copepoda, Harpacticoida, Cylindropsyllidae) with a description of three new species</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>147</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>419-472</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>de Le&#243;n-Gonz&#225;lez, Jes&#250;s Angel; Hern&#225;ndez-Guevara, Norma Ang&#233;lica; Rodr&#237;guez-Valencia, Jos&#233; Alejandro</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Paraonidae (Polychaeta) from western Mexico, with description of two new species</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>86</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>253-262</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R., J. Llewellyn-Hughes, P.D. Olson &amp; K. Nagasawa</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Small subunit rDNA and Bayesian inference reveal Pectenophilus ornatus (Copepoda incertae sedis) as highly transformed Mytilicolidae, and support assignment of Chondracanthidae and Xarifiidae to Lichomolgoidea (Cyclopoida).</Title><Series>Biological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>403-425</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R. S.  Conroy-Dalton</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Comparative Analysis of Vermiform Genera (Copepoda: Harpacticoida: Cylindropsyllidae), Including Descriptions of Boreovermis, New Genus and Bolbotelos, New Genus, from the Southern North Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Crustacean Biology</Series><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>206-223</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Golani, D.; Sonin, O.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>The Japanese threadfin bream &lt;i&gt;Nemipterus japonicus&lt;/i&gt;, a new Indo-Pacific fish in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>940-943</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dulcic, J.; Golani, D.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>First record of &lt;i&gt;Cyclopterus lumpus&lt;/i&gt; L., 1758 (Osteichthyes: Cyclopteridae) in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>69</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>300-303</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dickinson, E. C.; Bruce, M. D.; Dowsett, R. J.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Vivarium naturae or the naturalist's miscellany (1789&#8211;1813) by George Shaw: an assessment of the dating of the parts and volumes</Title><Series>Archives of Natural History</Series><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>322-343</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheerardyn, H., F. Fiers, M. Vincx &amp; M. De Troch</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Peltidiphonte gen. n., a New Taxon of Laophontidae (Copepoda: Harpacticoida) from Coral Substrates of the Indo-West Pacific Ocean</Title><Series>Hydrobiologia</Series><Volume>553</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>171-199</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Mesel, I.; Derycke, S.; Swings, J.; Vincx, M.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Role of nematodes in decomposition processes: Does within-trophic group diversity matter?</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>321</Volume><Pagination>157-166</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Eryilmaz, L.; Dalyan, C.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>First record of &lt;i&gt;Apogon queketti&lt;/i&gt; Gilchrist (Osteichthyes: Apogonidae) in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>69</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>1251-1254</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Troch, M.; Van Gansbeke, D.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Resource availability and meiofauna in sediment of tropical seagrass beds: Local versus global trends</Title><Series>Marine Environmental Research</Series><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>59-73</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheskiere, T.; Vincx, M.; Pison, G.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Are strandline meiofaunal assemblages affected by a once-only mechanical beach cleaning? Experimental findings</Title><Series>Marine Environmental Research</Series><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>245-264</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheerardyn, H., F. Fiers, M. Vincx &amp; M. Detroch</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Paralaophonte harpagone sp. n. (Copepoda: Harpacticoida), a laophontid with an extremely specialised maxilliped</Title><Series>Organisms Diversity &amp; Evolution</Series><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>323-324</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Verween, A.; Kerckhof, F.; Vincx, M.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>First European record of the invasive brackish water clam Rangia cuneata (G.B Sowerby I, 1831) (Mollusca: Bivalvia).</Title><Series>Aquatic Invasions</Series><Volume>1</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>198-203</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Derycke, S.; Backeljau, T.; Vlaeminck, C.; Vierstraete, A.; Vanfleteren, J.; Vincx, M.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Seasonal dynamics of population genetic structure in cryptic taxa of the Pellioditis marina complex (Nematoda: Rhabditida)</Title><Series>Genetica</Series><Volume>128</Volume><Issue>1-3</Issue><Pagination>307-321</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Ahn, K.</Authors><Year>2006</Year><Title>Replacement Name for the Genus Moorea Ahn (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae)</Title><Series>The Coleopterists Bulletin</Series><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>36-36</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Derycke, S.; Backeljau, T.; Vlaeminck, C.; Vierstraete, A.; Vanfleteren, J.; Vincx, M.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Spatiotemporal analysis of population genetic structure in Geomonhystera disjuncta (Nematoda, Monhysteridae) reveals high levels of molecular diversity</Title><Series>Marine Biology</Series><Volume>151</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><Pagination>1799-1812</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Ashton, G. V.; Willis, K. J.; Cook, E. J.; Burrows, M.</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Distribution of the introduced amphipod, Caprella mutica Schurin, 1935 (Amphipoda: Caprellida: Caprellidae) on the west coast of Scotland and a review of its global distribution</Title><Series>Hydrobiologia</Series><Volume>590</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>31-41</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheerardyn, H., M. De Troch, M. Vincx &amp; F. Fiers</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Spiniferaphonte, a new genus of Laophontidae (Copepoda: Harpacticoida), with notes on the occurrence of processes on the caudal rami.</Title><Series>Journal of Crustacean Biology</Series><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>309-318</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Sebastian, S.; Raes, M.; De Mesel, I.; Vanreusel, A.</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Comparison of the nematode fauna from the Weddell Sea Abyssal Plain with two North Atlantic abyssal sites</Title><Series>Deep Sea Research Part II: Topical Studies in Oceanography</Series><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>16-17</Issue><Pagination>1727-1736</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Troch, M.., M. Grego, V.A. Chepurnov &amp; M. Vincx</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Food patch size, food concentration and grazing efficiency of the harpacticoid Paramphiascella fulvofasciata (Crustacea, Copepoda).</Title><Series>Journal of Experimental Marine Biology and Ecology</Series><Volume>343</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>210-216</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Derycke, S.; Hendrickx, F.; Backeljau, T.; Dhondt, S.; Camphijn, L.; Vincx, M.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Effects of sublethal abiotic stressors on population growth and genetic diversity of Pellioditis marina (Nematoda) from the Westerschelde estuary</Title><Series>Aquatic Toxicology</Series><Volume>82</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>110-119</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Van Soest, R.W.M.; De Kluijver, M.J.; Van Bragt, P.H.; Faasse, M.; Nijland, R.; Beglinger, E.J.; de Weerdt, W.H.; de Voogd, N.J.</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Sponge invaders in Dutch coastal waters</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1733-1748</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Cevik, C.; Yokes, M.B.; Cavas, L.; Erkol, L.I.; Derici, O.B.; Verlaque, M.</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>First report of &lt;i&gt;Caulerpa taxifolia&lt;/i&gt; (Bryopsidales, Chlorophyta) on the Levantine coast (Turkey, Eastern Mediterranean)</Title><Series>Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</Series><Volume>74</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>549-556</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Ghekiere, A.; Fockedey, N.; Verslycke, T.; Vincx, M.; Janssen, C.</Authors><Year>2007</Year><Title>Marsupial development in the mysid Neomysis integer (Crustacea: Mysidacea) to evaluate the effects of endocrine-disrupting chemicals</Title><Series>Ecotoxicology and Environmental Safety</Series><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>9-15</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Derycke, S.; Fonseca, G.; Vierstraete, A.; Vanfleteren, J.; Vincx, M.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Disentangling taxonomy within the Rhabditis (Pellioditis) marina (Nematoda, Rhabditidae) species complex using molecular and morhological tools</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>152</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>1-15</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Derycke, S.; Remerie, T.; Backeljau, T.; Vierstraete, A.; Vanfleteren, J.; Vincx, M.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Phylogeography of the Rhabditis ( Pellioditis ) marina species complex: evidence for long-distance dispersal, and for range expansions and restricted gene flow in the northeast Atlantic</Title><Series>Molecular Ecology</Series><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>14</Issue><Pagination>3306-3322</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Munilla, T.; Soler Membrives, A.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Check-list of the pycnogonids from Antarctic and sub-Antarctic waters: zoogeographic implications</Title><Series>Antarctic Science</Series><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>99</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Franco, M.; Steyaert, M.; Cabral, H.; Tenreiro, R.; Chambel, L.; Vincx, M.; Costa, M.; Vanaverbeke, J.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Impact of discards of beam trawl fishing on the nematode community from the Tagus estuary (Portugal)</Title><Series>Marine Pollution Bulletin</Series><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><Pagination>1728-1736</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Park, J.; Jeon, M.; Ahn, K.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Description of Heterota sunjaei sp. nov. from Korean seashores and an annotated catalog of the littoral genus Heterota (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae: Aleocharinae)</Title><Series>Can Entomol</Series><Volume>140</Volume><Issue>01</Issue><Pagination>111-118</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Sak, S., S. Karaytug &amp; R. Huys</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Ciplakastacus gen. nov., a primitive genus of Leptastacidae (Copepoda, Harpacticoida) from the Mediterranean coast of Turkey</Title><Series>Journal of Natural History</Series><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>37-38</Issue><Pagination>2443-2459</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Abollo, E.; Ramilo, A.; Casas, S. M.; Comesa&#241;a, P.; Cao, A.; Carballal, M. J.; Villalba, A.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>First detection of the protozoan parasite &lt;i&gt;Bonamia exitiosa&lt;/i&gt; (Haplosporidia) infecting flat oyster &lt;i&gt;Ostrea edulis&lt;/i&gt; grown in European waters</Title><Series>Aquaculture</Series><Volume>274</Volume><Pagination>201-207</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Moodley, L.; Steyaert, M.; Epping, E.; Middelburg, J. J.; Vincx, M.; Van Avesaath, P.; Moens, T.; Soetaert, K.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Biomass-specific respiration rates of benthic meiofauna: Demonstrating a novel oxygen micro-respiration system</Title><Series>Journal of Experimental Marine Biology and Ecology</Series><Volume>357</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>41-47</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheerardyn, H., M. De Troch, S. Ndaro, M. Raes, M. Vincx &amp; A. Vanreusel</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Community structure and microhabitat preferences of harpacticoid copepods in a tropical reef lagoon (Zanzibar Island, Tanzania).</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the UK</Series><Volume>88</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>747-758</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Hyams-kaphzan, O.; Almogi-labin, A.; Sivan, D.; Benjamini, C.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Benthic foraminifera assemblage change along the southeastern Mediterranean inner shelf due to fall-off of Nile-derived siliciclastics</Title><Series>Neues Jahrbuch f&#252;r Geologie und Pal&#228;ontologie - Abhandlungen</Series><Volume>248</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>315-344</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Troch, M., J.L. Melgo-Ebarle,  L. Angsinco-Jimenez, H. Gheerardyn &amp; M. Vincx</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Diversity and habitat selectivity of harpacticoid copepods from sea grass beds in Pujada Bay, the Philippines</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>88</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>515-526</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Franco, M.; Soetaert, K.; Costa, M.; Vincx, M.; Vanaverbeke, J.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Uptake of phytodetritus by meiobenthos using 13C labelled diatoms and Phaeocystis in two contrasting sediments from the North Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Experimental Marine Biology and Ecology</Series><Volume>362</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>1-8</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Franco, M. A.; Soetaert, K.; Van Oevelen, D.; Van Gansbeke, D.; Costa, M.; Vincx, M.; Vanaverbeke, J.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Density, vertical distribution and trophic responses of metazoan meiobenthos to phytoplankton deposition in contrasting sediment types</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>358</Volume><Pagination>51-62</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Van Hoey, G.; Guilini, K.; Rabaut, M.; Vincx, M.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Ecological implications of the presence of the tube-building polychaete Lanice conchilega on soft-bottom benthic ecosystems</Title><Series>Marine Biology</Series><Volume>154</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1009-1019</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Fonseca, G.; Derycke, S.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Integrative taxonomy in two free-living nematode species complexes</Title><Series>Biological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>94</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>737-753</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Lipej, L.; Mavri&#269;, B.; &#381;i&#382;a, V.; Dul&#269;i&#263;, J.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>The largescaled terapon Terapon theraps : a new Indo-Pacific fish in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>73</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><Pagination>1819-1822</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Golani, D.; Appelbaum-Golani, B.; Gon, O.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Apogon smithi&lt;/i&gt; (Kotthaus, 1970) (Teleostei: Apogonidae), a Red Sea cardinalfish colonizing the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>72</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1534-1538</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Vanaverbeke, J.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Short-term changes in nematode communities from an abandoned intense sand extraction site on the Kwintebank (Belgian Continental Shelf) two years post-cessation</Title><Series>Marine Environmental Research</Series><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>240-248</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Rabaut, Marijn; Vincx, Magda; Degraer, Steven</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Do &lt;i&gt;Lanice conchilega&lt;/i&gt; (sandmason) aggregations classify as reefs? Quantifying habitat modifying effects</Title><Series>Helgoland Marine Research</Series><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>37-46</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Troch, M.; Chepurnov, V.; Vincx, M.; &#211;lafsson, E.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>The effect of Fucus vesiculosus on the grazing of harpacticoid copepods on diatom biofilms</Title><Series>Journal of Sea Research</Series><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>139-143</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Rabaut, M.; Braeckman, U.; Hendrickx, F.; Vincx, M.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2008</Year><Title>Experimental beam-trawling in Lanice conchilega reefs: Impact on the associated fauna</Title><Series>Fisheries Research</Series><Volume>90</Volume><Issue>1-3</Issue><Pagination>209-216</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Rabaut, M.; Degraer, S.; Schrijvers, J.; Derous, S.; Bogaert, D.; Maes, F.; Vincx, M.; Cliquet, A.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Policy analysis of the &#8216;MPA-process' in temperate continental shelf areas</Title><Series>Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems</Series><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><Pagination>596-608</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Ingels, J.; Kiriakoulakis, K.; Wolff, G. A.; Vanreusel, A.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Nematode diversity and its relation to the quantity and quality of sedimentary organic matter in the deep Nazar&#233; Canyon, Western Iberian Margin</Title><Series>Deep Sea Research Part I: Oceanographic Research Papers</Series><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><Pagination>1521-1539</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Galassi, D.M.P., R. Huys &amp; J.W. Reid</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Diversity, ecology and evolution of groundwater copepods.</Title><Series>Freshwater Biology</Series><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>691-708</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bussotti, S.; Guidetti, P.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Do Mediterranean fish assemblages associated with marine caves and rocky cliffs differ?</Title><Series>Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</Series><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>65-73</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Rosso, A.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>The first catenicellid (Bryozoa, Ascophora) from Mediterranean shallow waters: a hidden resident or a new immigrant</Title><Series>Journal of Natural History</Series><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>35</Issue><Pagination>2209-2226</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Armenteros, M.; Ruiz-Abierno, A.; Vincx, M.; Decraemer, W.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>A morphometric analysis of the genus Terschellingia (Nematoda: Linhomoeidae) with redefinition of the genus and key to the species</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>89</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1257-1267</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R. &amp; W. Lee</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Proposal of Marbefia, gen. n. and Inermiphonte, gen. n., including updated keys to the species of Pseudonychocamptus Lang, 1944 and Paralaophonte Lang, 1948 (Copepoda, Harpacticoida, Laophontidae)</Title><Series>ZooKeys</Series><Volume>23</Volume><Pagination>1-38</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Heiner, I.; Boesgaard, T. M.; Kristensen, R. M.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>First time discovery of Loricifera from Australian waters and marine caves</Title><Series>Marine Biology Research</Series><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>529-546</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Van Colen, C.; Montserrat, F.; Verbist, K.; Vincx, M.; Steyaert, M.; Vanaverbeke, J.; Herman, P.; Degraer, S.; Ysebaert, T.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Tidal flat nematode responses to hypoxia and subsequent macrofauna-mediated alterations of sediment properties</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>381</Volume><Pagination>189-197</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheerardyn, H., M. De Troch, M. Vincx &amp; A. Vanreusel</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Diversity and community structure of harpacticoid copepods associated with cold-water coral substrates in the Porcupine Seabight (North-East Atlantic)</Title><Series>Helgoland Marine Research</Series><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>53-62</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Harmelin, J.-G.; Bitar, G.; Zibrowius, H.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Smittinidae (Bryozoa, Cheilostomata) from coastal habitats of Lebanon (Mediterranean sea), including new and non-indigenous species</Title><Series>Zoosystema</Series><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>163-187</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>El-Rashidy, H.H. &amp; G.A. Boxshall</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Parasites Gained: Alien Parasites Switching to Native Hosts.</Title><Series>Journal of Parasitology</Series><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>1326-1329</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheerardyn, H., M. De Troch, M. Vincx &amp; A. Vanreusel</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Harpacticoida (Crustacea: Copepoda) associated with cold-water coral substrates in the Porcupine Seabight (NE Atlantic): species composition, diversity and reflections on the origin of the fauna</Title><Series>Scientia Marina</Series><Volume>73</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>747-760</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Aydin, I.; Bakir, K.; Galili, B.S.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>The first record of the Jinga shrimp, &lt;i&gt;Metapenaeus affinis&lt;/i&gt; (H. Milne Edwards, 1837) (Decapoda, Penaeidae) from the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Crustaceana</Series><Volume>82</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><Pagination>1091-1095</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Merckx, B.; Goethals, P.; Steyaert, M.; Vanreusel, A.; Vincx, M.; Vanaverbeke, J.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Predictability of marine nematode biodiversity</Title><Series>Ecological Modelling</Series><Volume>220</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><Pagination>1449-1458</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Schockaert, E. R.; Curini-Galletti, M.; De Ridder, W.; Volonterio, O.; Artois, T.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>A new family of lithophoran Proseriata (Platyhelminthes), with the description of seven new species from the Indo-Pacific and South America, and the proposal of three new genera</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>155</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>759-773</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Follesa, M. C.; Mulas, A.; Porcu, C.; Cau, A.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>First record of Chilomycterus reticulatus (Osteichthyes: Diodontidae) in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>74</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><Pagination>1677-1681</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dalyan, C.; Eryilmaz, L.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>The Arabian scad &lt;i&gt;Trachurus indicus&lt;/i&gt;, a new Indo&#8208;Pacific species in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Fish Biology</Series><Volume>74</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><Pagination>1615-1619</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Moreira, J.; D&#237;az-Agras, G.; Cand&#225;s, M.; Se&#241;ar&#237;s, M. P.; Urgorri, V.</Authors><Year>2009</Year><Title>Leptostracans (Crustacea: Phyllocarida) from the R&#237;a de Ferrol (Galicia, NW Iberian Peninsula), with description of a new species of &lt;em&gt;Nebalia&lt;/em&gt; Leach, 1814</Title><Series>Scientia Marina</Series><Volume>73</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>269-285</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Kerckhof, F.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Het mosdiertje &lt;i&gt;Bugula simplex&lt;/i&gt; Hincks, 1886 (Bryozoa, Cheilostomatida) nieuw voor de Belgische fauna [The bryozoan &lt;i&gt;Bugula simplex&lt;/i&gt; Hincks, 1886 (Bryozoa, Cheilostomatida) new species for the Belgian fauna]</Title><Series>De Strandvlo</Series><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>36-39</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.; Lan, T. C.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Description of &lt;i&gt;Scabrotrophon chunfui&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Gastropoda: Muricidae) from Northeast Taiwan and comments on &lt;i&gt;Nipponotrophon&lt;/i&gt; Kuroda &amp; Habe, 1971 and &lt;i&gt;Scabrotrophon&lt;/i&gt; McLean, 1996</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>37-42</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gofas, S.; Le Renard, J.; Bouchet, P.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Mollusca. in: Costello, M.J. et al. (eds), European Register of Marine Species: a check-list of the marine species in Europe and a bibliography of guides to their identification.</Title><Book>European register of marine species: a check-list of the marine species in Europe and a bibliography of guides to their identification</Book><Series>Patrimoines Naturels</Series><Volume>50</Volume><Pagination>180-213</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Vald&#233;s, &#193;.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Deep-water phyllidiid nudibranchs (Gastropoda: Phyllidiidae) from the tropical south-west Pacific Ocean</Title><Book>Tropical Deep-Sea Benthos</Book><Series>M&#233;moires du Mus&#233;um national d'Histoire naturelle. S&#233;rie A, Zoologie</Series><Volume>185</Volume><Pagination>331-368</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Cristobo, F.J; Urgorri, V.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Trachytedania&lt;/i&gt; (Porifera: Poecilosclerida) with a description of&lt;i&gt;Trachytedania ferrolensis&lt;/i&gt; sp.nov. from the north-east Atlantic.</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>81</Volume><Pagination>569-579</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Copepoda - Harpacticoida.</Title><Book>European register of marine species: a check-list of the marine species in Europe and a bibliography of guides to their identification</Book><Series>Collection Patrimoines Naturels</Series><Volume>50</Volume><Pagination>268-280</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Brandt, S.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Apicomplexa (free-living species)</Title><Book>European register of marine species: a check-list of the marine species in Europe and a bibliography of guides to their identification</Book><Series>Collection Patrimoines Naturels</Series><Volume>50</Volume><Pagination>40</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Smet, G.; Vincx, M.; Vanreusel, A.; Vanhove, S.; Vanaverbeke, J.; Steyaert, M.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Nematoda - free living</Title><Book>European register of marine species: a check-list of the marine species in Europe and a bibliography of guides to their identification</Book><Series>Collection Patrimoines Naturels, 50</Series><Pagination>161-174</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Chicoreus (Triplex) setionoi&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Gastropoda: Muricidae) from Arafura Sea, Pacific Ocean</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>145-148</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>van der Land, J.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Ctenophora</Title><Book>European register of marine species: a check-list of the marine species in Europe and a bibliography of guides to their identification</Book><Publisher>Collection Patrimoines Naturels</Publisher><Volume>50</Volume><Pagination>122-123</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Deprez, T.; Mees, J.; Wooldridge, T.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>MYSIDLAN 4.0 Taxonomy and biodiversity of shallow coastal Mysidacea of the Western Indian Ocean [CD-ROM]</Title><Series>Magda Vincx, Marine Biology Section: Gent</Series><Pagination>1 cd-rom</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huys, R.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Splanchnotrophid systematics: a case of polyphyly and taxonomic myopia.</Title><Series>Journal of Crustacean Biology</Series><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>106-156. (ii.2001)</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Carballo, J.L.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>On the genus &lt;i&gt;Coelocalypta&lt;/i&gt; (Porifera:Demospongiae) and other related fistulose halichondrid genera.</Title><Series>Cahiers de Biologie Marine</Series><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>255-262</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Berge, J.; Vader, W.; Galan, A.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Type material of Stegocephalidae Dana, 1855 (Crustacea, Amphipoda) in the collections of the Natural History Museaum, London, including the description of seven new species</Title><Series>Bull. nat. Hist. Mus. Lond. (Zool.)</Series><Volume>67</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>109-136</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Edwards, M.; John, A.W.G.; Johns, D.G.; Reid, P.C.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Case history and persistence of the non-indigenous diatom Coscinodiscus wailesii in the north-east Atlantic.</Title><Series>J. Mar. Biol. Ass. U.K.</Series><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>207-211</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Tita, G.; Desrosiers, G.; Vincx, M.; Gagn&#233;, J.-P.; Locat, J.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Diversity and vertical distribution of nematode assemblages: the Saguenay fjord (Quebec, Canada)</Title><Series>Cah. Biol. Mar.</Series><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>263-274</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>d'Hondt, J.-L.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Flustrina versus Neocheilostomina (Bryozoaires), remarques sur la biosystematique aux niveaux supraspecifiques</Title><Series>Bulletin de la Soci&#233;t&#233; zoologique de France, Systematique</Series><Volume>126</Volume><Pagination>391-406</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Neira, C.; Gad, G.; Arroyo, N. L.; Decraemer, W.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Glochinema bathyperuvensis sp. n. (Nematoda, Epsilonematidae): A new species from Peruvian bathyal sediments, SE Pacific Ocean</Title><Series>Contributions to Zoology</Series><Volume>70</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>147-159</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Sterrer, W.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Gnathostomulida from Australia and Papua New Guinea</Title><Series>Cah. Biol. Mar.</Series><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>363-395</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bitar, G.; Kouli-Bitar, S.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Nouvelles donn&#233;es sur la faune et la flore benthique de la c&#244;te Libanaise. Migration Lessepsienne.</Title><Series>Thalassia Salentina</Series><Volume>25</Volume><Pagination>71-74</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Blauwe, H.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Hypophorella expansa  Ehlers, 1876 een algemeen mosdiertje in aangespoelde kokers van de perkamentkokerworm Chaetopserus variopedatus [Hypophorella expansa Ehlers, 1876 a common bryozoan in beached Chaetopterus variopedatus tubes]. [Sic. The correct spelling is 'Chaetopterus']</Title><Series>De Strandvlo</Series><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>102-104</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Buzzurro, G.; Hoarau, A.; Greppi, E.; Pelorce, J.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Prima segnalazione di &lt;i&gt;Hinemoa cylindrica&lt;/i&gt; (de Folin, 1879) per il Mediterraneo</Title><Series>Bollettino Malacologico</Series><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>1-4</Issue><Pagination>23-26</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>&#199;evik, C.; &#214;zt&#252;rk, B.; Buzzuro, G.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>The presence of &lt;i&gt;Crassostrea virginica&lt;/i&gt; (Gmelin, 1791) and &lt;i&gt;Saccostrea commercialis&lt;/i&gt; (Iredale &amp; Roughley, 1933) in the Eastern Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>La Conchiglia</Series><Volume>298</Volume><Pagination>25-28</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>H&#248;isaeter, T.; Johanessen, P.J.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Xylodiscula planata&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov., a "lower" heterobranch gastropod from Norwegian waters</Title><Series>Sarsia</Series><Volume>86</Volume><Pagination>325-332</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mulder, J.P.M.; van Koningsveld, M.; Owen, M.; Rawson, J.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>COAST 3D: guidelines on the selection of CZM tools. Illustrated by applications to CZM problems on straight sandy coasts and on irregular coasts</Title><Series>Rapport RIKZ = Report RIKZ</Series><Publisher>Ministerie van Verkeer en Waterstaat. Rijksinstituut voor Kust en Zee (RIKZ)</Publisher><Volume>2001.02</Volume><Pagination>43 + appendices</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gonz&#225;lez, E.; Norambuena, R.; Garc&#237;a, M.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Initial allocation of harvesting rights in the Chilean fishery for Patagonian toothfish</Title><Book>Case studies on the allocation of transferable quota rights in fisheries</Book><Series>FAO Fisheries Technical Paper = FAO Document technique sur les p&#234;ches</Series><Pagination>304-321</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Golyshin, P.N.; Timmis, K.N.; Yakimov, M.M.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Oil eating bacteria</Title><Series>Bioworld</Series><Volume>1</Volume><Pagination>4-6</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Harrar, W.G.; Williams, A.J.; Barker, J.A.; Van Camp, M.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Modelling scenarios for the emplacement of palaeowaters in aquifer systems</Title><Book>Palaeowaters in coastal Europe: evolution of groundwater since the Late Pleistocene</Book><Series>Geological Society Special Publication</Series><Pagination>213-229</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Chavatte, N.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Het hyperbenthos van de Oosterschelde en de Westerschelde: seizoenaliteit en patronen op middellange termijn</Title><Publisher>Universiteit Gent. Marine Biologie. Instituut voor Dierkunde. Vakgroep Morfologie, Systematiek en Ecologie</Publisher><City>Gent</City><Pagination>148</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Seynaeve, P.; Verstuyft, P.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Onderzoek naar en ontwikkeling van een 1D numeriek model ter bepaling van de langskracht op een schip gedurende het vullen en ledigen van een sluiskolk</Title><Publisher>De Nayer Instituut</Publisher><City>St.-Katelijne-Waver</City><Pagination>xii, 177</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Svavarsson, J.; Kristj&#225;nsson, B.K.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Depth-size related patterns of marine isopods in the Nordic Seas</Title><Book>Isopod systematics and evolution</Book><Series>Crustacean Issues</Series><Pagination>277-288</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>de Louw, P.G.B.; Vermeulen, P.T.M.; Stuurman, R.; Reckman, J.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Waterconservering en peilbeheer in het BeNeLux-middengebied. Deelrapport 3: Bepaling van de effecten van waterconservering</Title><Publisher>TNO</Publisher><City>Delft</City></sequence><sequence><Authors>de Deckere, E.M.G.T.; Tolhurst, T.J.; de Brouwer, J.F.C.</Authors><Year>2001</Year><Title>Destabilisation of cohesive intertidal sediments by infauna</Title><Book>Faunal influence on sediment stability in intertidal mudflats</Book><Series>NIOO Thesis</Series><Pagination>31-38</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Massin, C.; Norro, A.; Mallefet, J.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Biodiversity of a wreck from the Belgian Continental Shelf: monitoring using scientific diving. Preliminary results.</Title><Series>Bulletin de l'Institut Royal des Sciences Naturelles de Belgique (Biologie)</Series><Volume>72</Volume><Pagination>67-72</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Borojevic, R.; Boury-Esnault, N.; Manuel, M.; Vacelet, J.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Order Leucosolenida Hartman, 1958. Pp. 1157-1184</Title><Book>Systema Porifera: a guide to the classification of sponges. 2 volumes</Book><Publisher>Kluwer Academic/Plenum</Publisher><City>NY</City><Pagination>1708 + xvliii</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Orsi Relini, L.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Occurrence of the South American fish &lt;i&gt;Pinguipes brasilianus&lt;/i&gt; (Pinguipedidae) in the Mediterranean</Title><Series>Cybium</Series><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>147-149</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Van Soest, R.W.M.; Hooper, J.N.A.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Order Spirophorida Bergquist &amp; Hogg, 1969. Pp. 83-84</Title><Book>Systema Porifera. A guide to the classification of sponges. 2 volumes.</Book><Publisher>Kluwer Academic / Plenum Publishers</Publisher><City>New York</City><Pagination>83-84</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huang, H.-L.; Liu, S.-F.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>One new species of free-living marine nematodes from southeastern beach of Xiamen Island</Title><Series>J. Oceanogr. Taiwan Strait = Taiwan Haixia</Series><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>177-180</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Lee, W. &amp; R. Huys</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>A new genus of groundwater Ameiridae (Copepoda, Harpacticoida) from boreholes in Western Australia and the artificial status of Stygonitocrella Petkovski, 1976.</Title><Series>Bulletin of the Natural History Museum Zoology Series</Series><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>39-50</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Sartoni, G.; Boddi, S.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Ceramium bisporum&lt;/i&gt; (Ceramiaceae, Rhodophyta), a new record for the Mediterranean algal flora</Title><Series>Botanica marina</Series><Volume>45</Volume><Pagination>566-570</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Davoult, D.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Faune et flore du littoral du Pas-de-Calais et de la Manche orientale: mise &#224; jour de la liste des esp&#232;ces d'Echinodermes [Fauna and flora of the Pas-de-Calais coast and the eastern English Channel: review of the echinoderm species list]</Title><Series>Rev. Trav. Stat. Mar. Wimereux</Series><Volume>2001</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><Pagination>1-3</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dumont, H.J. &amp; G.Y. Chiambeng</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>A third genus of freshwater calanoids (Copepoda, Diaptomidae, Diaptominae) in lowland tropical Africa: Camerundiaptomus, new genus.</Title><Series>Journal of Crustacean Biology</Series><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>619-626</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Caraus, I.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>The algae of Romania. Studii si Cercetari</Title><Series>Universitatea Bacau, Biologie</Series><Volume>7</Volume><Pagination>1-694</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Appeltans, W.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Phylogeny of the Holothuriidae (Echinodermata: Holothuroidea) inferred from morphology.</Title><Series>MSc Thesis. Vrije Universiteit Brussel: Brussel, Belgium</Series><Pagination>94</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Calles, A.K., L. Dom&#237;nguez, S. Guartatanga, V. Ruiz, K. Gonz&#225;lez, M.P. Cornejo R. De Gunauer &amp; M. Vincx</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Interannual variability of the meiobenthos and hyperbenthos communities from two Ecuadorian sandy beaches (1999-2001).</Title><Series>Investigaciones Marinas</Series><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1, Suppl. Symp., Valpara&#237;so</Issue><Pagination>135-137</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mu, F.H. &amp; R. Huys</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>New species of Stenhelia (Copepoda, Harpacticoida, Diosaccidae) from the Bohai Sea (China) with notes on subgeneric division and phylogenetic relationships.</Title><Series>Cahiers de Biologie Marine</Series><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>179-206</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Alvarez, B.; Bergquist, P.R.; Battershill, C.N.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Taxonomic revision of the genus &lt;i&gt;Latrunculia&lt;/i&gt; Du Bocage (Porifera: Demospongiae: Latrunculiidae) in New Zealand</Title><Series>New Zealand Journal of Marine and Freshwater Research</Series><Volume>36</Volume><Pagination>151-184</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Simonini, R.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Distribution and ecology of the genus &lt;i&gt;Ophryotrocha&lt;/i&gt; (Polychaeta: Dorvilleidae) in Italian harbours and lagoons</Title><Series>Vie Milieu</Series><Volume>52</Volume><Pagination>59-65</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gheskiere, T.; Hoste, E.; Kotwicki, L.; Degraer, S.; Vanaverbeke, J.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>The sandy beach meiofauna and free-living nematodes from De Panne (Belgium)</Title><Series>Bulletin de l'Institut Royal des Sciences Nature lles de Belgique</Series><Volume>72</Volume><Issue>Suppl.</Issue><Pagination>43-49</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Faasse, M.; De Blauwe, H.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>De exotische samengestelde zakpijp Botrylloides violaceus Oka, 1927 in Nederland (Ascidiacea: Pleurogona: Styelidae) [The exotic colonial tunicate Botrylloides violaceus Oka, 1927 in the Netherlands (Ascidiacea: Pleurogona: Styelidae)]</Title><Series>Het Zeepaard</Series><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><Pagination>136-141</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Blauwe, H.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Determinatie en verspreiding van Tricellaria inopinata d'Hondt &amp; Occhipinti Ambrogi (Bryozoa, Cheilostomatida), een recente immigrant uit het noorden van de Stille Oceaan</Title><Series>Het Zeepaard</Series><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>73-88</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Newman, L. J.; Cannon, L. R. G.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>The genus Cycloporus (Platyhelminthes: Polycladida) from Australasian waters.</Title><Series>Raffles Bulletin of Zoology</Series><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>287-299</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Description of a new muricopsine species (Gastropoda: Muricidae) from Martinique, Lesser Antilles</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>139-140</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mienis, H.K.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Marine molluscs from the Eastern Mediterranean 9. Again a new Indo-Pacific migrant: &lt;i&gt;Diodora funiculata&lt;/i&gt;.</Title><Series>Spirula</Series><Volume>327</Volume><Pagination>73</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>&#199;eviker, D.; Albayrak, S.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>New record of an exotic Bivalve from the southeastern coast of Turkey: &lt;i&gt;Scapharca inflata&lt;/i&gt; (Reeve, 1844)</Title><Series>La Conchiglia</Series><Volume>305</Volume><Pagination>56-60</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Deboeuf, C.; Herrier, J.-L.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>The restoration of mudflats, salt marshes and dunes on the eastern bank of the Yzer-rivermouth, Nieuwpoort</Title><Book>Littoral 2002: 6th International Symposium Posters: a multi-disciplinary Symposium on Coastal Zone Research, Management and Planning, Porto, 22-26 September 2002: volume 3</Book><Pagination>201-202</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Van Hooydonk, E. (Ed.)</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>De Belgisch-Nederlandse verkeersverbindingen: de Schelde in de XXIste eeuw</Title><Series>Antwerpse Zeerechtdagen</Series><Publisher>Maklu</Publisher><City>Antwerpen</City><Pagination>521</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Oreskes, N.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Gravity surveys in the "permanent" ocean basins: An instrumental chink in a theoretical suit of armor</Title><Book>Oceanographic history: The Pacific and beyond. Proceedings of the Fifth International Congress on the History of Oceanography, La Jolla, California, July 1993</Book><Pagination>502-510</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Missiaen, T.; Henriet, J.-P.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Chemical munition dump sites in coastal environments: a border-transgressing problem</Title><Book>Chemical munition dump sites in coastal environments</Book><Pagination>1-12</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Morcos, S.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>The educational mission of marine sciences: A case study of East Africa, the early initiatives, 1930-80</Title><Book>Oceanographic history: The Pacific and beyond. Proceedings of the Fifth International Congress on the History of Oceanography, La Jolla, California, July 1993</Book><Pagination>215-223</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>European federation of Marine Science and Technology Societies; Hellenic Oceanographers Association</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Oceanographical Aspects for a Sustainable Mediterranean. First Scientific Conference: Athens 27-29 September 2002. [CD-ROM]</Title><Publisher>[S.n.]</Publisher><Pagination>1 cd-rom</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Viaene, P.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Advies i.v.m. een wijziging van het toevoerdebiet naar de nevengeul aan het stuwcomplex van Oudenaarde</Title><Publisher>Waterbouwkundig Laboratorium en Hydrologisch Onderzoek</Publisher><City>Antwerpen</City><Pagination>7</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>de Boer, M. N.; Baldwin, R.; Burton, C. L. K.; Eyre, E. L.; Jenner, K. C. S.; Jenner, M-N., M.; Keith, S. G.; McCabe, K. A.; Parsons, E. C. M.; Peddemors, V. M.; Rosenbaum, H. C.; Rudolph, P.; Simmonds, M. P.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Cetaceans in the Indian Ocean sanctuary: a review</Title><Publisher>Whale and Dolphin Conservation Society (WDCS)</Publisher><City>UK</City><Pagination>53</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Maas, J.; Van de Guchte, C.; Kerkum, F.C.M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Methodebeschrijvingen voor de beoordeling van verontreinigde waterbodems volgens de TRIADE benadering: Methodebeschrijvingen voor enkele bioassays en veldstudies</Title><Series>RIKZ Nota</Series><Volume>93,027</Volume><Pagination>79</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Rogie, H.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Met Oostende als uitvalbasis: Belgi&#235; activeert zijn operationele capaciteit voor bestrijding olievervuiling op zee</Title><Series>Neptunus (Zeebrugge)</Series><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>269</Issue><Pagination>258-259</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Cox, R.J. (Ed.)</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Proceedings on CD-ROM of the 30th PIANC-AIPCN Congress, 22-26 September 2002, Sydney, Australia</Title><Publisher>PIANC = AIPCN</Publisher><City>Brussel</City><Pagination>1 CD-ROM</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Tang, C.M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Orsten deposits from Sweden: Miniature Late Cambrian arthropods</Title><Book>Exceptional fossil preservation: a unique view on the evolution of marine life</Book><Pagination>117-130</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Boyd, S.E.; Brown, C.; Schratzberger, M.</Authors><Year>2002</Year><Title>Future developments</Title><Book>Guidelines for the conduct of benthic studies at aggregate dredging sites</Book><Pagination>92-94</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mifsud, C.; Ovalis, P.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>A note on new discoveries and the distribution of a few Mollusca from the Eastern Mediterranean</Title><Series>La Conchiglia</Series><Volume>306</Volume><Pagination>20-25</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dauvin, J.-C.; Dewarumez, J.-M.; Gentil, F.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Liste actualis&#233;e des esp&#232;ces d'Ann&#233;lides Polych&#232;tes pr&#233;sentes en Manche [An up to date list of polychaetous annelids from the English Channel].</Title><Series>Cahiers de Biologie Marine</Series><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>67-95</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Clarke, A.; Johnston, N.M</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Antarctic marine benthic diversity</Title><Series>Oceanography and Marine Biology: an Annual Review</Series><Volume>41</Volume><Pagination>47-114</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Faasse, M.; Ates, R.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>De Nederlandse polyclade platwormen (Platyhelminthes: Turbellaria: Polycladida) II De uit Amerika afkomstige &lt;i&gt;Euplana gracilis&lt;/i&gt;</Title><Series>Het Zeepaard</Series><Volume>63</Volume><Pagination>57-60</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Two new muricids (Gastropoda: Muricidae) from west Africa</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>2-3</Issue><Pagination>51-56</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Description of three new species of &lt;i&gt;Trophon&lt;/i&gt; s.l. Montfort, 1810 (Gastropoda: Muricidae) from Chile</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>101-110</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>&#199;inar, M. E.; Ergen, Z.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Eusyllinae and Syllinae (Annelida: Polychaeta) from northen Cyprus (Eastern Mediterranean Sea) with a checklist of species reported from the Levant Sea</Title><Series>Bulletin of Marine Science</Series><Volume>72</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>769-793</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Belmonte, G.; Bussotti, S.; Costantini, F.; Denitto, F.; Metrangolo, M.; Muscogiuri, L.; Onorato, R.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Indagine faunistica sulle grotte sottomarine del Capo di Leuca (Mar Ionio-Puglia)</Title><Series>Biol. Mar. Medit.</Series><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>647-649</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Kerckhof, F.; Stegenga, H.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Nieuwe &lt;i&gt;Polysiphonia&lt;/i&gt;-soorten voor Belgi&#235; en Noord-Frankrijk, met een gereviseerde determineertabel voor de soorten van het geslacht &lt;i&gt;Polysiphonia&lt;/i&gt; in deze regio [New &lt;i&gt;Polysiphonia&lt;/i&gt; species for Belgium and Northern France, with a revised key to the species of the genus &lt;i&gt;Polysiphonia&lt;/i&gt; in this region]</Title><Series>Dumortiera</Series><Volume>80</Volume><Pagination>40-45</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Fraussen, K.; Hadorn, R.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Six new Buccinidae (Mollusca: Gastropoda) from New Caledonia</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>2-3</Issue><Pagination>33-50</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mienis, H.K.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Mariene Mollusken  uit het Oostelijk deel van de Middellandse zee 15. Invasie van rugschilden van &lt;i&gt;Sepia pharaonis&lt;/i&gt; langs de kust van Israel.</Title><Series>SPIRULA- Correspondentieblad van de Nederlandse Malacologische Vereniging</Series><Volume>335</Volume><Pagination>127-129</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bussotti, S.; Guidetti, P.; Belmonte, G.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Distribution patterns of the cardinal fish, Apogon imberbis, in shallow marine caves in southern Apulia (SE Italy)</Title><Series>Ital. J. Zoolog.</Series><Volume>70</Volume><Pagination>153-157</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mienis, H.K.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Marine molluscs from the Eastern Mediterranean 14. The first finds of &lt;i&gt;Octopus cyanea&lt;/i&gt;</Title><Series>Spirula</Series><Volume>333</Volume><Pagination>88-89</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mienis, H.K.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Marine molluscs from the Eastern Mediterranean 11. A first find of &lt;i&gt;Cerithium columna&lt;/i&gt; Sowerby, 1834</Title><Series>Spirula</Series><Volume>331</Volume><Pagination>31-32</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Hovda, J.I. &amp; A. Fosshagen</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Hyperbenthic calanoids and Thespesiopsyllus paradoxus (Sars) collected with a light trap in western Norway.</Title><Series>Sarsia</Series><Volume>88</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>89-94</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Moraes, F.C.; Muricy, G.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Taxonomy of &lt;i&gt;Plakortis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Plakinastrella&lt;/i&gt; (Demospongiae: Plakinidae) from oceanic islands off north-eastern Brazil, with description of three new species.</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>83</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>385-397</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Turpaeva, E. P.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Shallow water sea spiders (Pycnogonida) from the Kuril, Commander, and Yamskii Islands. 2. Pycnogonidae family.</Title><Series>Pycnogonidae family ZooL. Zhurn.</Series><Volume>82</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><Pagination>577-583</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gokoglu, M.; Bodur, T.; Kaya, Y.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>First record of the Red Sea bannerfish (&lt;i&gt;Heniochus intermedius&lt;/i&gt; Steindachner, 1893) from the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Israel Journal of Zoology</Series><Volume>49</Volume><Pagination>324-325</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bachelet, G.; Dauvin, J.-C.; Sorbe, J. C.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>An updated checklist of marine and brackish water Amphipoda (Crustacea: Peracarida) of the southern Bay of Biscay (NE Atlantic)</Title><Series>Cah. Biol. Mar.</Series><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>121-151</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Vandendriessche, S.; Degraer, S.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Drijvende wieren als habitat voor macrofauna aan de Belgische kust [Floating seaweeds as habitat for macrofauna at the Belgian coast].</Title><Series>De Strandvlo</Series><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>50-57</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Scapolatempo, M.; Solustri, C.; Sabelli, B.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Amathina tricarinata&lt;/i&gt; (Linnaeus, 1767) (Orthogastropoda, Heterobranchia, Amathinidae): una nuova specie esotica in Mediterraneo</Title><Series>Biologia Marina Mediterranea</Series><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>614-617</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Vilvens C. &amp; H&#233;ros V.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Description of &lt;i&gt;Herpetopoma eboreum&lt;/i&gt; n.sp. (Gastropoda : Trochidae: Eucyclinae: Chilodoniini) from New Caledonia.</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>2-3</Issue><Pagination>61-65</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dewicke, A.; Cattrijsse, A.; Mees, J.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Spatial patterns of the hyperbenthos of subtidal sandbanks in the southern North Sea</Title><Series>Journal of Sea Research</Series><Volume>49</Volume><Pagination>27-45</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Maes, F.; Lavrysen, L.; Maes, F.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Integraal waterbeleid in Vlaanderen en Nederland</Title><Series>Actualia Milieurecht</Series><Publisher>Die Keure</Publisher><City>Brugge</City><Volume>1</Volume><Pagination>XIII, 358 + bijlage</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Princen, S.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Evaluation of the ecological success of a reforested mangrove system in a Sri Lankan lagoon</Title><Publisher>Free University Brussels. Laboratory of Plant Science and Nature Management</Publisher><City>Brussel</City><Pagination>51</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mennen, W.; Warmoes, T.; Awouters, R.; Denayer, B.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Nieuwe kansen voor de Jeker vanuit Vlaams perspectief</Title><Book>Nieuwe kansen voor de Jeker, internationaal symposium = nouvelles chances pour le Geer, symposium international</Book><Pagination>[1-15]</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Year>2003</Year><Title>Generic depth-damage relationships for residential structures without basements: economic guidance memorandum #04-01</Title><Publisher>[S.n.]</Publisher><Pagination>17</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Hydrologisch Informatiecentrum</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>De digitale Demer: een nieuw en krachtig instrument voor waterpeilbeheer [BROCHURE]</Title><Publisher>Waterbouwkundig Laboratorium en Hydrologisch Onderzoek</Publisher><City>Antwerpen</City><Pagination>24</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>de Albergaria Ferreira Pinto, J.S.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Caracteriza&#231;&#227;o nutricional da dourada (&lt;i&gt;Sparus aurata&lt;/i&gt;) criada em regime semi-intensivo: influencia da pratica do jejum nas caracteristicas nutricionais e organolepticas</Title><Publisher>Instituto Superior de Ci&#234;ncias da Sa&#250;de-Sul</Publisher><City>Lisboa</City><Pagination>82, 23</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Year>2003</Year><Title>Abdichtung beim Westerschelde-Tunnel und bei der Metro Kopenhagen = Seals for the Westerschelde tunnel and the Copenhagen metro</Title><Volume>8</Volume></sequence><sequence><Authors>Moreteau, J.-Cl.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Comparaison de mod&#232;les de croissance chez &lt;i&gt;Pinna nobilis&lt;/i&gt; et autres mollusques</Title><Book>Premier S&#233;minaire International sur la Grande nacre de M&#233;diterran&#233;e &lt;i&gt;Pinna nobilis&lt;/i&gt;, 10-12 octobre 2002, &#206;le des Embiez, Var, France</Book><Series>M&#233;moires de l'Institut oc&#233;anographique Paul Ricard</Series><Pagination>63-76</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Faasse, M.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>De Nederlandse polyclade platwormen (Platyhelminthes: Turbellaria: Polycladida): 3. De cryptogene &lt;i&gt;Stylochus flevensis&lt;/i&gt; (Hofker, 1930)</Title><Series>Het Zeepaard</Series><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><Pagination>153-158</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Smith, K.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Hydrogeologische studie te Koksijde: kunstmatige infiltratie als bijdrage tot duurzame waterwinning in kustgebieden</Title><Publisher>Universiteit Gent, Faculteit Wetenschappen, Vakgroep Geologie en Bodemkunde, Onderzoekseenheid Toegepaste Geologie en Hydrogeologie</Publisher><City>Gent</City><Pagination>168</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dauwe, B.; Peters, B.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Plan van aanpak MOVE: toeleverende studies aan het MOVE evaluatierapport 2003: evaluatierapport 2003</Title><Publisher>Rijksinstituut voor Kust en Zee (RIKZ)</Publisher><Pagination>25 (7)</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Brouwer, K.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Kaneel, cassia, kardemom... Vraag en aanbod op de Mukh&#226;wi markt voor kleine specerijen in de vroege zeventiende eeuw, naar Nederlandse documenten</Title><Book>In het kielzog: Maritiem-historische studies aangeboden aan Jaap R. Bruijn bij zijn vertrek als hoogleraar zeegeschiedenis aan de Universiteit Leiden</Book><Pagination>141-162</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Hamerlynck, O.; Mees, J.; Craeymeersch, J.A.; Soetaert, K.; Hostens, K.; Cattrijsse, A.; Van Damme, P.A.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>The Westerschelde estuary: two food webs and a nutrient rich desert</Title><Book>The demersal fish and macro-invertebrate assemblages of the Westerschelde and Oosterschelde estuaries (Southern Bight of the North Sea) = De demersale vis- en macro-invertebraten gemeenschappen van de Westerschelde en Oosterschelde estuaria (Zuidelijke Bocht van de Noordzee)</Book><Pagination>157-164</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Seys, J. (Ed.)</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>VLIZINE december 2003</Title><Series>Nieuwsbrief VLIZINE</Series><Publisher>Vlaams Instituut voor de Zee (VLIZ)</Publisher><City>Oostende</City><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>12</Issue></sequence><sequence><Authors>Blount, B.G.</Authors><Year>2003</Year><Title>Perceptions of legitimacy in conflict between commercial fishermen and regulatory agencies</Title><Book>Values at sea: ethics for the marine environment</Book><Pagination>127-146</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Year>2003</Year><Title>2003 Annual Combined Cumulative Index for Cambridge Scientific Abstracts Journals [CD-ROM]</Title><Publisher>Cambridge Scientific Abstracts</Publisher><City>Bethesda</City><Pagination>cd-rom</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Blauwe, H.; Faasse, M. A.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Smittoidea prolifica&lt;/i&gt; Osburn, 1952 (Bryozoa, Cheilostomatida), a Pacific bryozoan introduced to The Netherlands (Northeast Atlantic).</Title><Series>Bulletin van het Koninklijk Belgisch Instituut voor Natuurwetenschappen. Biologie</Series><Volume>74</Volume><Pagination>33-39</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>P&#233;rez, T.; Vacelet, J.; Bitar, G.; Zibrowius, H.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Two new lithistids (Porifera: Demospongiae) from a shallow eastern Mediterranean cave (Lebanon)</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>15-24</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Chan, T.-Y.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>The "Plesionika rostricrescentis (Bate, 1888)" and "P. lophotes Chace, 1985" species groups of Plesionika Bate, 1888, with descriptions of five new species (Crustacea: Decapoda: Pandalidae)</Title><Book>Tropical Deep-Sea Benthos 23</Book><Series>M&#233;moires du Mus&#233;um national d'Histoire naturelle (1993)</Series><Volume>191</Volume><Pagination>293-318</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Serejo, C. S.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Cladistic revision of talitroidean amphipods (Crustacea, Gammaridea), with a proposal of a new classification</Title><Series>Zoologica Scripta</Series><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><Pagination>551-586</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.; Quiquandon, P. &amp; Briano, B.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Chicoreus (Triplex)&lt;/i&gt; (Gastropoda: Muricidae) from Madagascar</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>143-146</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Review of Recent species of &lt;i&gt;Morula&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Oppomorus&lt;/i&gt;), &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Azumamorula&lt;/i&gt;), and &lt;i&gt;M.&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Habromorula&lt;/i&gt;) (Gastropoda: Muricidae: Ergalataxinae)</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>91-130</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Huyse, T.; Malmberg, G.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Molecular and morphological comparisons between Gyrodactylus ostendicus n. sp. (Monogenea: Gyrodactylidae) on Pomatoschistus microps (Kroyer) and G. harengi Malmberg, 1957 on Clupea harengus membras</Title><Series>Systematic Parasitology</Series><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>105-113</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dumoulin, E.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Snelle areaaluitbreiding van het penseelkrabbetje Hemigrapsus penicillatus (de Haan, 1835) langs de kusten van de Zuidelijke Bocht van de Noordzee, status van haar opmars in de Westerschelde en beschouwingen over de ecologie en het gedrag van de soort</Title><Series>De Strandvlo</Series><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>5-35</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dahdouh-Guebas, F.; De Bondt, R.; Abeysinghe, P.D.; Kairo, J.G.; Cannicci, S.; Triest, L.; Koedam, N.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Comparative study of the disjunct zonation pattern of the grey mangrove Avicennia marina (Forsk.) Vierh. In Gazi Bay (Kenya</Title><Series>Bulletin of Marine Science</Series><Volume>74</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>237-252</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Schmidt, D.N.; Thierstein, H.R.; Bollmann, J.; Schiebel, R.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Abiotic Forcing of Plankton Evolution in the Cenozoic</Title><Series>Science</Series><Volume>303</Volume><Pagination>207-210</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mienis, H. K.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Marine molluscs from the Eastern Mediterranean 19. The first finds of &lt;i&gt;Chama aspersa&lt;/i&gt; Reeve, 1846.</Title><Series>Spirula</Series><Volume>337</Volume><Pagination>34-35</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mart&#237;, R.; Uriz, M.J.; Ballesteros, E.; Turon, X.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Temporal variation of several structure descriptors in animal-dominated benthic communities in two Mediterranean caves</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>573-580</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Mart&#237;, R.; Uriz, M.J.; Ballesteros, E.; Turon, X.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Benthic assemblages in two Mediterranean caves: species diversity and coverage as a function of abiotic parameters and geographic distance</Title><Series>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</Series><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>557-572</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Dominguez-Granda, L.; Fockedey, N.; De Mey, M.; Beyst, B.; Cornejo, M.d.P.; Calderon, J.; Vincx, M.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Spatial patterns of the surf zone hyperbenthic fauna of Valdivia Bay (Ecuador)</Title><Series>Hydrobiologia</Series><Volume>529</Volume><Pagination>205-224</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>FAO</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>FAO fisheries technical papers: a selected digital collection [CD-ROM]</Title><Publisher>FAO</Publisher><City>Rome</City><Pagination>1 cd-rom</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Year>2004</Year><Title>Vis uit de Baltische Zee = Fish of the Baltic Sea</Title><Publisher>Office for Official Publications of the European Communities</Publisher><City>Luxembourg</City><Pagination>52, ill.</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Rilov, G.; Benayahu, Y.; Gasith, A.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Prolonged lag in population outbreak of an invasive mussel: a shifting-habitat model</Title><Series>Biological Invasions</Series><Volume>6</Volume><Pagination>347-364</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Year>2004</Year><Title>Caring for the sea: accomplishments, activities and future of the United Nations GESAMP</Title><Series>IOC Information Documents</Series><Publisher>UNESCO</Publisher><City>Paris</City><Volume>1197</Volume><Pagination>14</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>S&#225;nchez, R.P.; Bezzi, S. (Ed.)</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Los peces marinos de inter&#233;s pesquero. Caracterizaci&#243;n biol&#243;gica y evaluaci&#243;n del estado de explotaci&#243;n</Title><Series>El Mar Argentino y sus recursos pesqueros</Series><Publisher>INIDEP</Publisher><City>Mar del Plata</City><Volume>4</Volume><Pagination>357</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Year>2004</Year><Title>Naar een duurzame Belgische visserijsector: analyserapport bij het strategisch plan voor de Stichting voor Duurzame Visserijontwikkelling: eindrapport</Title><Publisher>Policy Research Corporation</Publisher><City>Antwerpen</City><Pagination>44</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Eco Consult Milieucommunicatie (Ed.)</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Maatschappelijke kosten batenanalyse voor de actualisatie van het Sigmaplan: conclusies op hoofdlijnen</Title><Publisher>Ministerie van de Vlaamse Gemeenschap. Afdeling Zeeschelde</Publisher><City>Antwerpen</City><Pagination>120</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Fraschetti, S.; Rossi, F.; Guarnieri, G.; Terlizzi, A.; Boero, F.; Herman, P.M.J.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Biodiversity-substratum interactions on hard substrata</Title><Series>MarBEF Newsletter</Series><Volume>1</Volume><Pagination>26</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Van de Woestyne, T.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Biologische kennis als alternatief voor chemische bestrijding van de brakwatermossel: Gametogenesis-opvolging van de brakwatermossel</Title><Publisher>Universiteit Gent. Faculteit Wetenschappen</Publisher><City>Gent</City></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gonsaeles, G.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Het CCR-verdrag inzake de verzameling, afgifte en inname van afval in de Rijn- en binnenvaart</Title><Book>Zeeverontreiniging: preventie, bestrijding en aansprakelijkheid</Book><Series>Antwerpse Zeerechtdagen</Series><Pagination>251-267</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Smith, H.D.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>The Belgian sea</Title><Book>Report of the Workshop on Marine Spatial Planning, Gent, January 16-17, 2004</Book><Pagination>28-29</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Lubke, R.A.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Vegetation dynamics and succession in sand dunes of the eastern coasts of Africa</Title><Book>Coastal dunes: Ecology and conservation</Book><Series>Ecological Studies</Series><Pagination>67-84</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Holm, N.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Reduce marine litter: Save the North Sea project results</Title><Publisher>Alterra</Publisher><City>The Netherlands</City><Pagination>17</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Barjadze, Sh.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Annotated List of Aphids (Hemiptera: Drepanosiphidae) in Georgia</Title><Series>Proceedings of the Institute of Zoology</Series><Volume>22</Volume><Pagination>193-197</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Plinius</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Graanbouw</Title><Book>De wereld &lt;i&gt;Naturalis historia&lt;/i&gt;</Book><Pagination>393-414</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>P&#233;queux, A.; S&#233;bert, P.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Le co&#251;t &#233;nerg&#233;tique des &#233;changes d'ions: l'exemple des crustac&#233;s euryhalins = The energetic cost of ionic exchange: The example of euryhaline crustaceans</Title><Series>Oc&#233;anis (Paris)</Series><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>311-329</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bijlsma, A.C.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>Study of density currents in the framework of the LTV for the Scheldt estuary: executive summary</Title><Publisher>Waterbouwkundig Laboratorium en Hydrologisch Onderzoek</Publisher><City>Antwerp</City><Pagination>31</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>MacKenzie, B.R.</Authors><Year>2004</Year><Title>MARBEF investigates biodiversity of fish</Title><Series>MarBEF Newsletter</Series><Volume>1</Volume><Pagination>12</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Schultz, H.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Sea Urchins: a guide to worldwide shallow water species</Title><Series>Heinke &amp; Peter Schultz Partner, Hemdingen</Series><Pagination>484</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Neira, C.; Decraemer, W.; Backeljau, T.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>A new species of Glochinema (Epsilonematidae: Nematoda) from the oxygen minimum zone of Baja California, NE pacific and phylogenetic relationships at species level within the family</Title><Series>Cah. Biol. Mar.</Series><Volume>46</Volume><Pagination>105-126</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Terlizzi, A.; Scuderi, D.; Fraschetti, S.; Anderson, M. J.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Quantifying effects of pollution on biodiversity: a case study of highly diverse molluscan assemblages in the Mediterranean</Title><Series>Marine Biology</Series><Volume>148</Volume><Pagination>293-305</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Massin, C.; Appeltans, W.; Van Hoey, G.; Vincx, M.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Leptosynapta minuta (Becher, 1906) (Echinodermata, Holothuroidea), a new record for Belgian marine waters</Title><Series>Belg. J. Zool.</Series><Volume>135</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>83-86</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Lelong, P.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Capture d'un macabit, &lt;i&gt;Epinephelus merra&lt;/i&gt; Bloch, 1793 (Poisson, Serranidae), en Mediterranee nord-occidentale</Title><Series>Marine Life</Series><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue></sequence><sequence><Authors>Gavrilova, N. A.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>New for the Black Sea Tintinnids species</Title><Series>Ekologiya moria</Series><Volume>69</Volume><Pagination>5-11</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Houart, R.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Description of a new species of &lt;i&gt;Favartia&lt;/i&gt; (Gastropoda: Muricidae: Muricopsinae) from Brazil</Title><Series>Novapex</Series><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>1-2</Issue><Pagination>41-44</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Lehnert, H.; Stone, R.; Heimler, W.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Two new species of &lt;i&gt;Plakina&lt;/i&gt; Schulze, 1880 (Porifera, Plakinidae) from the Aleutian Islands (Alaska, USA)</Title><Series>Zootaxa</Series><Volume>1068</Volume><Pagination>27-3</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Streftaris, N.; Zenetos, A.; Papathanassiou, E.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Globalisation in marine ecosystems: the story of non-indigenous marine species across European seas</Title><Series>Oceanogry and Marine Biology: an Annual Review</Series><Volume>43</Volume><Pagination>419-453</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Esteves, E.L.; Muricy, G.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>A new species of &lt;i&gt;Stelletta&lt;/i&gt; (Demospongiae, Astrophorida) without microscleres from Abrolhos Archipelago, Northeastern Brazil</Title><Series>Zootaxa</Series><Volume>1006</Volume><Pagination>43-52</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Jaume, D.; Br&#233;hier, F.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>A new species of Typhlatya (Crustacea: Decapoda: Atyidae) from anchialine caves on the French Mediterranean coast</Title><Series>Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</Series><Volume>144</Volume><Pagination>387-414</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Galil, B.S.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Contribution to the knowledge of Leucosiida III. Urnalana gen. nov. (Crustacea: Brachyura)</Title><Series>Zoologische Mededelingen</Series><Volume>79</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>9-40</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Galil, B. S.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Contribution to the knowledge of Leucosiida IV. Seucolia gen. nov. (Crustacea: Brachyura)</Title><Series>Zoologische Mededelingen</Series><Volume>79</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><Pagination>41-59</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Musco, Luigi; Giangrande, Adriana</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>A new sponge-associated species, &lt;i&gt;Syllis mayeri&lt;/i&gt; n. sp. (Polychaeta: Syllidae), with a discussion on the status of &lt;i&gt;S. armillaris&lt;/i&gt; (M&#252;ller, 1776)</Title><Series>Scientia Marina</Series><Volume>69</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>467-474</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Scott, F.J.; Marchant, H.J. (Ed.)</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Antarctic marine protists</Title><Series>Australian Biological Resources Study</Series><Pagination>563</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Calles, A.; Vincx, M.; Cornejo, P.; Calder&#243;n, J.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Patterns of meiofauna (especially nematodes) in physical disturbed Ecuadorian sandy beaches</Title><Series>Meiofauna Marina</Series><Volume>14</Volume><Pagination>121-129</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Cruz-Barraza, J.A.; Carballo, J.L.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>First record of &lt;i&gt;Plakortis&lt;/i&gt; Schulze (Porifera:  Homosclerophorida) from the Northeast Pacific coast, with the description of &lt;i&gt;Plakortis albicans&lt;/i&gt; sp. nov.</Title><Series>Zootaxa</Series><Volume>868</Volume><Pagination>1-12</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Derycke, S.; Remerie, T.; Vierstraete, A.; Backeljau, T.; Vanfleteren, J.; Vincx, M.; Moens, T.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Mitochondrial DNA variation and cryptic speciation within the free-living marine nematode Pellioditis marina</Title><Series>Marine Ecology Progress Series</Series><Volume>300</Volume><Pagination>91-103</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Vandendriessche, S.; Messiaen, M.; Vincx, M.; Degraer, S.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Juvenile Hippocampus guttulatus from a neuston tow at the French-Belgian border</Title><Series>Belg. J. Zool.</Series><Volume>135</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><Pagination>101-102</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Galil, B. S.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Dorippe quadridens&lt;/i&gt; (Decapoda, Dorippidae) - first record of alien Dorippid in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Crustaceana</Series><Volume>78</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><Pagination>497-498</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>De Blauwe, H.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>A new species of&#160;Caulibugula&#160;(Bryozoa: Cheilostomatida) from France</Title><Series>Bull. Kon. Belg. Inst. Natuurwet. Biologie</Series><Volume>75</Volume><Pagination>81-87</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>D&#237;az, M.C.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Common sponges from shallow marine habitats from Bocas del Toro region, Panama</Title><Series>Caribbean Journal of Science</Series><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>465-475</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Chimenz Gusso, C.; d'Hondt, J.L.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>Finding of &lt;i&gt;Pherusella brevituba&lt;/i&gt; Soule, 1951 (Bryozoa Ctenostomatida, Pherusellidae) in the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Bollettino del Museo Civico di Storia Naturale di Verona</Series><Volume>29</Volume><Pagination>85-88</Pagination></sequence><sequence><Authors>Bitar, G.; Dupuy de la Grandrive, R.; Foulquie, M.; Verlaque, M.</Authors><Year>2005</Year><Title>&lt;i&gt;Neomeris annulata&lt;/i&gt; Dickie (Dasycladales, Chlorophyceae): a potential new invader from the Red Sea to the Mediterranean Sea</Title><Series>Cryptogamie. Algologie</Series><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><Pagination>309-317</Pagination></sequence></dataset>